# WILLIAM BRENDEL

He / Him / His

ADVISOR • STRATEGIST • INNOVATOR • PIONEER

brendel.william@gmail.com +1 (415) 539-5322 linkedin.com/in/william-brendel

### SUMMARY

Snap Inc. amazon Google **Software Engineering:** 20+ years

Machine Learning (ML): 18+ years 2x Founder

**Tech Industry:** 13+ years 30+ patents and publications in Al

Fluent in English and French Management and product strategy: 8+ years

# TOGETHER, WE SUCCEED

In need to grow your business and team, to scale your product strategy, or to use new technologies to keep up with competition, and in front of a fast changing business landscape, you may be indecisive on how to execute. I spent more than a decade helping top tech companies like Google, Amazon, and Snap, shipping products that are used by 100+ millions of users daily. Thinking outside the box, focusing on MVPs, being agile, failing, iterating and learning fast, being user-centric, and leading by example, are how, together, we succeed.

### **EDUCATION**

PhD in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

June 2011

Master in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, CPE Lyon, France

### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

#### Inovexus

Mentor / Advisor July 2023 - Present

Giving back to entrepreneurs by sharing my experience both as a Technical and Product Executive:

- Currently mentoring 2 startups, invyo.io and quideos.com
- \$2M seed funding raised after 9 months in the mentorship program

#### Crossroads Venture Studio, Inc.

#### Founder / General Partner

May 2023 - Present

Provide the initial team, strategic direction to reach product-market fit, and execution to startup launch:

- 8+ projects, including automarketer.ai see our portfolio: crossroadventurestudio.com
- 62.5% success rate (seed funding and/or bootstrapping to first customer)

#### Heali Al

#### Co-Founder / Chief Science Officer / Head of Product

May 2019 - May 2023

Co-founded a health-tech startup to help people with chronic disease to reduce their symptoms via personalized nutrition:

- Recruited and directed a team of 2-12 engineers, product designers, and UX researchers
- Architected and implemented Al-based nutrition technologies, supporting 200+ medical conditions
- \$4M fundraised, 8 digits business valuation

#### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

#### Snap Inc.

### Technical Program Manager / Senior Research Scientist

May 2016 - May 2019

Supported Snap's research team's growth and monitored 40+ projects impacting 188M+ DAU:

- 10+ research domains, including face analysis, NLP, scene understanding, augmented reality, video analysis
- Published: privacy-preserving friend recommendation 14% revival of dead users, 7% user engagement
- Designed: Bitmoji recommendation in the chat interface 8% increase in user engagement

#### Amazon • A9

#### Machine Learning Researcher / Technical Product Manager

November 2012 - May 2016

Defined, developed, and shipped products for A9's visual search team, servicing 200M+ DAU:

- Spearheaded our mobile brand logo detection and recognition project real-time performance at 100fps
- Blueprinted the visual search database, the annotation and evaluation platform 12M+ images and labels

### Google • Youtube

#### Machine Learning Engineer

August 2011 - November 2012

Initiated and supervised the Suggested Edits project – an automatic system for poor-quality video detection and correction:

- Engineered and scaled the feature to the entire YouTube video corpus, impacting 94M+ DAU
- Created 10+ various video effects and filters

### SCIENTIFIC COMMUNITY SERVICE

### IEEE/CVF Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition

➡ Publication Chair May 2017 - May 2019

Coordinated the publication process for 2 editions, with 2000+ papers issued for each edition.

#### **IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision**

Publication Chair
May 2018 − May 2019

Organized the publication process for WACV18, with 200+ papers released for the year.

# SKILLS, QUALITIES, VALUES AND PERSONALITY



